MARINI, Gustavo Martin

E-mail: gustavommarini@gmail.com

Mobile: +39 3455256990

Skype: gustavommarini

Date of Birth: 11 of November 1983

CAREER STATEMENT

Passionate developer with more than 10 years of experience. Very advocate and fascinated with Web and Mobile development and with the latest design concepts. Application and web developer focused on Javascript, CSS, React, React Native. Constantly learning cutting edge technologies and tools. I was involved in projects embraces agile methodologies. Team Player, versatile, self-taught and very positive attitude are some of my personal skills.

RELEVANT SKILLS

- FrontEnd Related Knowledges: HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, Javascript, PHP, SASS, Compass, LESS, Twitter Bootstrap, Foundation, Yeoman, JSON, Ink (for responsive emails), AJAX, AngularJS, React, React Native, Storybook, GraphQL, Ruby on Rails, Wordpress and Drupal. I use GIT for a version control system. I'm diving in Full Stack development with NodeJS, Express and MongoDB.
- Previous BE development: C#, .Net 3.5/4.0, Visual Studio 2010, Java with Hibernate, Spring and ZK, GIT, MySQL, PostgreSQL and SQLite.
- Learned at University: Pascal, Modula2, VisualBasic (.Net), C, C++, Prolog, Lisp, Struts, Joomla, Python and Delphi.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

ADDI (COLOMBIA)

2022 - 2024

Developing the clients website with NextJS (React) which interacts with a REST BE using axios and uses redux as state management. Also I have been updating some quick internal projects using Retool.

But I was mainly involved in the development of the mobile app using React Native, interacting with REST at the beginning but when we started with the revamp of the app the BE changed using GraphQL. The state management was done with redux.

We started working with a monorepo with Lerna, but with the revamp project we moved to Nx as the tool to manage the monorepo. Also I have done unitary testing using Jest and React Native Testing Library.

In all of the React and React Native projects we strongly use TypeScript. And we document every important matter on Notion.

Also to keep track of the different events that occur on the mobile app, but also on the web app we use Amplitude. Every new feature was implemented using split and its feature toggles (or feature flags), which allows developers to switch a feature of an application on or off without having to re-deploy code into the production environment.

Position Summary

- Joining an already formed team that works on the React Native project, where all of us engineers were Senior developers.
- Working on React (NextJS) from scratch from a blank project.
- Evaluating and checking Merge Request of the FrontEnd team
- In an active role in meetings with the rest of the team, PM and stakeholders.
- Coordinating tasks with the rest of the team.
- Writing documentation on Notion

Technology used

HTML5, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, React, NextJS, React Native, Styled Components, TypeScript, Axios, Redux, Jest, Storybook, REST API, Nx, Lerna, GraphQL, Amplitude and Split.

PUZZLE (ARGENTINA)

2021 - 2024

Developing a website with React for internal management related to the puzzle professionals (all the information regarding personal information, seniority, english level, assigned projects, rate, etc), projects (name, start date, members, state, etc) and integration with Clickup tools (tracking hours, working flows, state of tasks, etc). Using GraphQL as query language for APIs.

Also working on an app with React Native. This app has an Intro screen that you can swipe and the rest of the app is basically used to reproduce videos, doing surveys and earning badges according to the videos watched and the surveys completed.

On both development, we use Styled Components to enhance CSS for styling React and React Native components and TypeScript to improve the React experience.

I was in charge of developing a banking React Native app that use Typescript. Unitary testing was made with Jest and E2E tests using Detox, also Storybook was implemented here and GraphQL was used as query language. The app used an iOS SDK due to that we had to implement a bridge in swift. All the project was highly documented on each step, decision made and technologies used along side with comparatives among the possible options on each of these cases. Using Jira to track the different tasks.

GIT for version control. Working using scrum methodology.

Position Summary

- Joining an already formed team that works on the React project.
- Working on React Native from scratch form a blank project.
- Evaluating and checking Merge Request of the FrontEnd team
- In an active role on meetings with the client representing the FrontEnd team and helping the PM.
- Coordinating tasks with the rest of the team.

Technology used

HTML5, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, React, React Native, Styled Components, TypeScript, Jest, Detox, Storybook and GraphQL.

BENKNER IT GMBH (GERMANY)

2020 - 2021

Developing a website with React to manage and communicate with a mobile app using React-Native and Expo. The states where managed with Redux on the website and MobX on the app. Working with React Hooks in function components. Regarding visual appearance, we use the framework Kitten UI on the app and Material UI on the website. GIT for version control. Working using scrum methodology. Also in the app we use Storybook to show the component isolated.

Learning and working a bit with the Backend development in NodeJS, Express, MongoDB and Mongoose. Mainly small tasks.

Position Summary

- Setting up an environment for React Native development with Expo.
- Working on React Native from scratch. Start using Redux for state management and later change to MobX.
- Understanding and adapting an administration theme (FUSE) to work and communicate with the app.
- Developing some tasks for the Backend.

Technology used

HTML5, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, React, React Native, Material-UI, Kitten-UI, Storybook, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB and Mongoose. And as state management I used MobX and Redux.

FREELANCER WEB AND APP DEVELOPER/DESIGNER

2011 - NOW

The key tasks on the projects in which I was involved were to develop websites using several CMS in order to expose companies or personal information. Also working in personal projects with React and React Native. All this jobs were done while I was traveling in a van through LatinAmerica.

Position Summary

- Gathering all the requirements from the client and proposing ideas to help them to have an excellent user experience.
- Ensuring Graphic design on each one of the sites and doing some research to fill out them with content.
- Developing whole websites from scratch and adapting already existing themes.
- Installing and setting up the CMS.
- Testing websites on several browsers (IE, Chrome, Safari and Firefox just to name a few).

Technology used

SASS, Compass, LESS, Foundation, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, PHP, JQuery, Yeoman, React and React Native. And I used CMS as Wordpress and Drupal.

GLOBANT (ARGENTINA)

2015 - 2017

Developing a web application for Deloitte using HTML, CSS, SASS, Compass, Javascript, Twitter Bootstrap, Kendo UI and AngularJS. Using TFS for source code manager. Working using scrum methodology. There I was moved up as the FrontEnd lead of the project.

I was also a mentor in a UI Course to strengthen the knowledge in UI technologies (HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery and AngularJS) to the Backend referents on the same account.

Technology used

Web development languages, tools and frameworks: HTML, CSS, SASS, Compass, Javascript, Kendo UI, AngularJS, Twitter Bootstrap, and TFS as source code manager.

LIQUID INTERACTIVE (BRISBANE - AUSTRALIA)

2014 - 2015

Developing web sites using HTML, CSS, Less, SASS, Compass, JQuery, Javascript, Twitter Bootstrap and Drupal CMS also making accessible web content, tested with NVDA tool among others. HTML5 banners, using HTML, CSS, Javascript and GSAP for the animations. Responsive EDMs. Developing sites with Angularjs using Yeoman and the Angular generator. I had been doing some testing tasks using Selenium tools.

I have used Tortoisesvn as a subversion client and also GIT as a version control system.

I have been working with companies as Devine, Isuzu and Brisbane City Council.

Position Summary

- Developing landing pages.
- Developing Responsive EDMs
- Developing HTML5 banners
- Updating and developing new features in several sites.
- Doing maintenance and testing tasks for different websites.

Technology used

Web development languages, tools and frameworks: HTML, CSS, Less, SASS, Compass, Javascript, JQuery, GSAP, Ink, Twitter Bootstrap, Angularjs, Yeoman, Drupal CMS and Tortoisesvn as a subversion client and GIT as a version control.

DESIGN APPLICATION PTY LTD (BRISBANE - AUSTRALIA)

2014 - 2015

Here I worked as a Full Stack developer, building and designing a web application using Ruby on Rails, HTML, HAML, CSS, SASS, JQuery, Javascript, Twitter Bootstrap, MySQL and PostgreSQL. Also using GIT as a version control system and deploying the application in Heroku.

Position Summary

- Designing, developing and testing the website.
- Setting up the Ruby on Rails environment.

Technology used

Web development languages, tools and frameworks: HTML, HAML, CSS, SASS, Twitter Bootstrap, Ruby on Rails, MySQL, PostgreSQL and GIT as a version control.

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPMENT FOR TUSK AGENCY (MELBOURNE - AUSTRALIA)

2014

I did some research for them, set up a Wordpress multisite for testing purposes and repair some issues in other Wordpress website.

Position Summary

- Setting up a test Wordpress multisite.
- Analyzing other site to identify the issues that arise and the changes needed.
- Applying the changes needed.

Technology used

Web development languages and CMS: PHP, HTML, CSS and Wordpress.

CITY HALL OF PUERTO MADRYN

2013 - 2014

I worked for a couple of months on a project using Java, Hibernate and Spring frameworks. As database engine we used PostgreSQL, Glassfish and JBoss as application servers. This project was the core of a system to unificate all the little programs and worksheets that were currently coexisting on the city hall.

Later I was promoted as Web technical referent role. There I developed an institutional web page prototype, using Drupal, Foundation (for responsive design), HTML5, CSS3 and JQuery. I also took responsibilities on the graphic designer tasks. Also developing Wordpress themes for different areas of the city hall. One of them (the "Ente Mixto de Turismo") following an Agile methology with weekly meetings between users/clients and Graphic designers. It was developed using Wordpress, Foundation 3, SASS, Compass, PHP, HTML5, CSS3 and JQuery.

Moreover I also develop Wordpress plugins to help removing unnecessary information and/or widgets for the user, adding widgets with information in order to achieve the ease of access concept and other visual modifications.

Finally I developed the UI of the Puerto Madryn's captive portal which is used to access to the free internet service on the main square. Also I developed the UI of an application to read and create QR Codes with addresses in the city and integrated it with the Google Maps API.

Position Summary

- Developing and leading all the web projects.
- Interacting with graphic designers to achieve the projects.
- Adapting a design made by a group of graphic designers to a web project.
- Researching and studying about technologies and components to use.
- Dealing with user's needs and on-demand requests and with tight deadlines.

- Responsive design development and browser and mobile testing (IE, Chrome, Firefox, Safari and mobile devices).
- Technical analysis of business logic features.
- Tasks estimation.
- Code review, bug fixing and provide support to the final user.

Technology used

Web development languages, tools and frameworks: HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, PHP, SASS, Compass, Twitter Bootstrap, Foundation, Yeoman, Wordpress and Drupal. Application development languages, tools and frameworks: Java, Hibernate, Spring, PostgreSQL, Glassfish and JBoss.

FREELANCER DESKTOP APPLICATIONS

2010 - 2012

The main desktop application that I have developed by myself (the first one in collaboration with a partner) were the followings:

- Developing a custom application for managing a gastronomic establishment in C#. Which manages mysql databases, network communications between one or more terminals, has printer interfaces with both fiscal and common ticket printers and interact with spreadsheets in Excel to import and export tables. I worked with a partner who developed an Android application integrated to this system to help waiters to take note and billing.
- Developing a custom application for doctors in which they have the clinic history of their patients, besides that, it holds their personal data. It was made in C# language with management of mysql databases.

Position Summary

- Gathering all the requirements from the client and proposing ideas to help them to have an excellent user experience.
- Designing the architecture and deciding which the best tools for the project are.
- Developing the application
- Testing the application, bugs fixing and bringing support to the final user
- Delivering the application and setting up the environment.

Technology used

Using tools as Visual Studio 2010, C# (.Net), .Net Framework 4.0 and 3.5, Mysql and SQLite to develop the applications.

NET **A**DMINISTRATOR

2012 - 2014

Performing network administrator tasks, such as supporting and maintaining the school's networks. In addition to this I was in charge of selecting and updating the suitable software for the "Conectar Igualdad" program in School 728 - Alfonsina Storni, in the city of Puerto Madryn, Chubut, Argentina.

LANGUAGES SPANISH

Native

ENGLISH

6 years in "Asociación Argentina de Cultura Inglesa" (1995 - 2001). With a final score of 6.

TOEFL IBT exam on January of 2014 with a score of 86.

I lived in Australia for a year.

ITALIAN

Living in Salerno since the end of 2022. Almost fluid, but still learning

EDUCATION

DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCES. (COMPARABLE TO AN AUSTRALIAN BACHELOR DEGREE WITH A MAYOR IN COMPUTING.)

2002 - 2011

Universidad Nacional del Sur - Bahia Blanca, Buenos Aires, Argentina.

COMPUTER TECHNICIAN PERSONAL AND PROFESSIONAL

1999 - 2001

Technical Education College N°1 "Fray Luis Beltrán" - Salliqueló, Buenos Aires, Argentina.